You've now learned so
much about deep learning and
sequence models that we can actually
describe a trigger word system
quite simply just on one slide,
as you see in this video.
But with the rise of speech recognition,
that there have been more and
more devices you can wake
up with your voice and
those are sometimes called
trigger word detection systems.
So let's see how you can
build a trigger word system.
Examples of trigger word systems
include the Amazon Echo,
which is woken up with the word Alexa,
the Baidu DuerOS powered devices
woken up with the phrase xiaodunihao,
Apple Siri working up with hey, Siri, and
Google Home woken up with okay, Google.
So it's thanks to trigger word
detection that if you have, say,
an Amazon Echo in your living room,
you can walk in your living room and
just say, Alexa, what time is it?
And have it wake up or be triggered by the
word Alexa and answer your voice query.
So if you can build a trigger word
detection system, maybe you can make your
computer do something by telling it,
computer, activate.
One of my friends also
worked on turning on and
off a particular lamp using a trigger
word kind of as a fun project.
But what I want to show you is how you can
build a trigger word detection system.
The literature on trigger detection
algorithm is still evolving so there isn't
wide consensus yet on what's the best
algorithm for trigger word detection.
So I'm just going to show you one
example of an algorithm you can use.
Now, you've seen RNNs like this and
what we really do is take an audio clip,
maybe compute spectrogram features.
And that generates features, x1,
x2, x3 audio features, x1, x2,
x3 that you pass through an RNN.
And so all that remains to be done
is to define the target labels.
Y
So if this point in the audio clip
is when someone just finished saying
the trigger word, such as Alexa or
xiaodunihao or hey, Siri, or okay,
Google, then in the training sets,
you can set the target labels to be 0 for
everything before that point and right
after that to set the target label of 1.
And then if a little bit later on,
the trigger word was said again and
the trigger word was said at this point,
then you can again set the target
label to be 1 right after that.
Now, this type of labelling scheme for
an RNN could work.
Actually, this will actually
work reasonably well.
One slight disadvantage of this
is it creates a very imbalanced
training set to have
a lot more 0s than 1s.
So one other thing you could do,
this is a little bit of a hack, but
could make the model a little bit easier
to train is instead of setting only
a single time step output 1, you can
actually make it output a few 1s for
several times or for a fixed period
of time before reverting back to 0.
So and that slightly evens
out the ratio of 1s to 0s,
but this is a little bit of a hack.
But if this is when in the audio
clipper the trigger word is said,
then right after that,
you can set the target label to 1, and
if this is the trigger word said again,
then right after that is when
you want the RNN to output 1.
So you get to play more of this as
well in the programming exercise.
But I think you should feel quite proud of
yourself that you've learned enough about
deep learning that it just
takes one picture and
one slide to describe something as
complicated as trigger word detection.
And based on this,
I hope you'll be able to implement
something that works and allows you to
detect trigger words when you see
more of this in the program exercise.
In this course on sequence models,
you learned about our RNNs,
including both GRUs and LSTMs,
and then in the second week,
you learned a lot about word embeddings
and how to learn representations of words.
And then in this week,
you learned about the attention model
as well as how to use it
to process audio data.
And I hope you have fun implementing
all of these ideas in this week's
program exercise.